<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Unix Supremacist</title>
<description>Unix Supremacist's Updates</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/rss/xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://unix-supremacist.github.io/rss/xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
<title>Minor update: mupen64plus tutorial updated</title>
<guid>mupen64plusgliden64</guid>
<link>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/gaming/linuxgaming.html</link>
<description>
updated mupen64plus tutorial to include how to install gliden64 on arch.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New Page: Gaming on Unix</title>
<guid>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/tech/linuxgaming.html</guid>
<link>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/gaming/linuxgaming.html</link>
<description>
this is a new guide for gaming on unix, there is some todo sections but there is a lot here already.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>RSS feed launch?</title>
<guid>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/rss/xml</guid>
<link>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/rss/xml</link>
<description>
this should be the launch of my rss feed, currently i manually am editing
the xml file, i hope to provide site updates via this, but i'm afraid i'll trigger regrabbing
in certain rss feed readers.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Fall of Minecraft Modpacks</title>
<guid>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/posts/tfom.html</guid>
<link>https://unix-supremacist.github.io/posts/tfom.html</link>
<description>
<h2>1. The Beginning
<a name="1. The Beginning"></a>
</h2>


<h3>1.1. Feed The Beast
<a name="1.1. Feed The Beast"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">The first minecraft modpack i
know if is the original feed the beast skyblock, for
minecraft versions 1.0-1.2.5, it was just a skyblock map
with a few mods, nothing to note as far as complexity but it
seems to have been met with a overwhelmingly positive
response and is where it all started.</p>

<h3>1.2. Ultimate
<a name="1.2. Ultimate"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">After their success their were
other modpacks, but the only thing worth mentioning is the
original tekkit. FTB continued to make modpacks, which as
far as i'm aware, lead to next FTB Ultimate</p>

<p style="margin-top: 1em">FTB Ultimate is probably where
modpacks started to morph into the long progression based
playstyle we see today, it had mods like IndustrialCraft,
Gregtech, Thermal Expansion, Forestry, Railcraft,
Buildcraft, RedPower, and much more. it was also a survival
mode in a normal world not a skyblock, and is generally one
of the packs the most people have nostalgia for.</p>

<p style="margin-top: 1em">Post Ultimate for FTB there were
many packs, unhinged, unleashed, monster, etc, etc, and to
great success though with the lack of RedPower some people
still stayed behind on Ultimate. and ofcourse the community
outside of FTB was rising, though i don't really feel
a need to mention them in this post.</p>

<h3>1.3. Infinity
<a name="1.3. Infinity"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">In 1.7.10 FTB Released a few
packs, none of them more noteworthy than Infinity. Infinity
is a "Kitchen Sink" pack with basically everything
you could imagine up to that point. you have
IndustrialCraft, EnderIO, Thermal Expansion, Twilight
Forest, Thaumcraft, Botania, in general if there was
something you wanted to do, or a popular mod you wanted to
play, it was there, and everything worked, though this
isn't the reason Infinity is well known anyway</p>

<h3>1.4. Evolved
<a name="1.4. Evolved"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">In later updates Infinity was
renamed Infinity Evolved and got a new concept introduced.
gamemodes. expert mode changed how the game plays and tied
mods together, and ported some of the original Gregtech
nerfs into script form, it brought back the long progression
of Ultimate to the praise of many, except it was even
better, longer, and more fun.</p>

<h2>2. Post 1.7.10
<a name="2. Post 1.7.10"></a>
</h2>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">After 1.7.10 and the age of
Infinity ended there was successors, Infinity Lite and FTB
Beyond, but nothing stuck packs kept trying to scratch that
itch and they did, for a lot of people, but thats how we got
to the state of modded we are in now, people trying to
scratch that itch, during this time a lot of people also
found Gregtech 5, which is known for it's grind, this
only accelerated the downward spiral of modpacks post
Infinity.</p>

<h2>3. The Problem
<a name="3. The Problem"></a>
</h2>


<h3>3.1. Playablity
<a name="3.1. Playablity"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">You may ask what is the problem
with modern modpacks how they are, you enjoy them and
don't see the issue. if you do enjoy them, great that
you do! the problem is right now that modpacks are very
specialized for certain playstyles, you have sink packs that
are just a ton of mods without a single recipe change making
them extremely unbalanced. you have expert packs where every
recipe is changed and the pack takes months to complete.
with this not only is finding good packs in your style hard,
it's also hard to find packs you can play with your
friends and you all agree on it, for us who don't like
singleplayer and don't care for most of these modern
packs, it makes it extremely difficult to play modpacks.</p>

<p style="margin-top: 1em">A great example of this problem
is Gregtech New Horizons, and AllTheMods, both are fine
packs in their own way, but have major issues for me to
actually play them, AllTheMods (refering to the 1.12
version) is unbalanced and is hard for me to take seriously,
not to mention can be a short pack for the same reasons,
Gregtech New Horizons is the exact opposite, it's so
long it's hard for me to personally not get bored,
plus my friends will definitely get bored, so it's
hard to ever get a playthrough going, these packs are fine
for their audiences, but why do they have to be the
mainstream?</p>

<h3>3.2. Performance
<a name="3.2. Performance"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">Generally modern packs have poor
performance this comes down to a mix between incompetence
and wanting to just throw every mod under the sun at a pack,
it just doesn't work. most 1.12 packs use 4-8gb of
ram, to me this is unacceptable along with the low
framerates and low tps,</p>

<h2>4. The Solution
<a name="4. The Solution"></a>
</h2>


<h3>4.1. Playablity
<a name="4.1. Playablity"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">Making packs that are balanced
selectively like FTB Infinity Evolved was the normal, this
way everyone can play, you can have long strings of
progression without making everything grindy, hell you could
even limit it to certain mods, or just OP items. that way
everyone can have fun, no bullshit required.</p>

<h3>4.2. Performance
<a name="4.2. Performance"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">For 1.12 just checking your mods
goes a long way, most memory usage and poor performance is
caused by one or two mods being silly, example of mods that
are bad on 1.12 would be, EnderIO, Mekanism, NuclearCraft,
TerraFirmaCraft, AdventOfAcension, Binnie's Mods, and
a few others, generally this is just quality assurance shit
people fail at.</p>

<h2>5. Extra Notes
<a name="5. Extra Notes"></a>
</h2>


<h3>5.1. TestPackPleaseIgnore
<a name="5.1. TestPackPleaseIgnore"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">Another great pack at doing
balance and it was even before infinity just less popular,
is TestPackPleaseIgnore, it's basically everything
infinity is but with less nerfs and long tech trees, and
more just balancing out OP items, it also has more mods like
Gregtech 4, and Ars Magica, definitely a treat and a prime
example of how to do things.</p>

<h3>5.2. AllOfFabric3
<a name="5.2. AllOfFabric3"></a>
</h3>


<p style="margin-top: 1em">In modern times one pack that
manages to strike this balance pretty well, that i
don't like over modlist stablity reasons, is
AllOfFabric3, it has basically every popular fabric mod,
performs well over optimization mods and a half decently
managed modlist, OP items are tweaked, with Modern
Industrialization filling the progression, it fills the itch
more than any other sink or "expert" pack does at
the moment.</p>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>